In order for a program to be really useful,
من أجل أن يكون برنامج ما مفيداً حقاً،
it needs to interact with real-world data.
عليه أن يتعامل مع بيانات من أرض الواقع.
Images, web pages, and databases are all examples of files,
الصور وصفحات الإنترنت وقواعد البيانات كلها أمثلة على ملفات،
and we routinely create, move,
ونقوم بصورة روتينية بإنشائها وتحريكها
manipulate, and read these files in our daily digital lives.
وتعديلها وقراءتها في حياتنا الرقمية اليومية.
All the data we've used so far has been defined inside
كافة البيانات التي استخدمناها حتى الآن كانت محددة
the Python script or raw input from the user during execution of the script.
داخل برنامج Python النصي أو المدخلات الخام من المستخدم خلال تنفيذ البرنامج النصي.
Next, we're going to massively increase the variety of what we can achieve in
سنقوم تالياً بزيادة تنوّع ما يمكننا إنجازه بشكل كبير
our Python programming by introducing how to read and write files in Python.
في البرمجة بلغة Python من خلال التعرف على كيفية قراءة وكتابة الملفات في Python.
This will allow us to interact with and process
سيتيح هذا لنا التفاعل مع ومعالجة
larger amounts of information from many more sources.
كميات أكبر من المعلومات من مصادر أكثر.
All kinds of files have a similar structure on a computer.
تمتلك كافة أنواع الملفات تركيبة متشابهة على جهاز الحاسوب.
There are strings of characters that encode some information.
هناك سلاسل من رموز تقوم بتشفير بعض المعلومات.
The specific file format,
التنسيق المحدد للملف،
often indicated by the extension of the file name such as.py,
وعادة ما يشار إليه بامتداد الملف مثل py.،
TXT, HTM, CSV, and many more,
أو txt أو htm أو csv وغيرها الكثير،
will indicate how those characters are organized.
سيشير إلى كيف يتم ترتيب تلك الرموز.
The characters in a file are interpreted by
تتم ترجمة الرموز في ملف ما
the various programs we use to interact with them.
بواسطة البرامج المختلفة التي نستخدمها للتعامل معها.
For example, an image editing program will interpret
مثلاً، سيترجم برنامج تحرير صور
the information of a digital photograph file and display the image.
معلومات ملف صورة رقمية ويعرض الصورة.
If we then edit the image in the program,
ثم إذا قمنا بالتعديل على الصورة في البرنامج
were using this program to make changes to the characters in the file.
فإننا بذلك نستخدم هذا البرنامج لإجراء تعديلات على الرموز الموجودة داخل الملف.
In Python, we can read those file characters directly.
في لغة Python، يمكننا قراءة رموز تلك الملفات مباشرة.
The experience will seem quite different from opening a file in a desktop application.
ستبدو التجربة مختلفة كثيراً عن فتح ملف ما في تطبيق على سطح المكتب.
Opening files in Python gives us
فتح الملفات في Python
a common programmatic interface to all kinds of
يمنحنا واجهة برمجية شائعة لكافة أنواع الملفات
files without the need for a graphical user interface,
من دون الحاجة إلى واجهة مستخدم رسومية،
which means we can automate tasks involving files with Python programs.
ما يعني أنه بإمكاننا أتمتة مهمات تتعلق بملفات بواسطة برامج Python.